<tool id="fgenesh_split" name="FGENESH split" version="@TOOL_VERSION@+galaxy@VERSION_SUFFIX@" profile="@PROFILE@" >
    <description>fasta sequences</description>
    <macros>
	  <import>macros.xml</import>
    </macros>
    <expand macro="requirements" />
    <expand macro="stdio" />
    <command><![CDATA[
	    mkdir -p contigs &&
	    #if $output_file_extension == "default":
	    	split_multi_fasta.pl $input_fasta -name $filename_format -dir contigs/ 
	    #else
	    	split_multi_fasta.pl $input_fasta -name $filename_format -dir contigs/ -ext $output_file_extension
	    #end if

	    ]]></command>
    <inputs>
	    <param name="input_fasta" type="data" format="fasta,fasta.gz" label="Fasta file"/>
	    <param name="filename_format" type="select" label="Output filename format" help="Default: count">
            	<option value="count" selected="True">sequential count</option>
            	<option value="seq_id">Use Sequence Header from the input fasta file</option>
	    </param>
	    <param name="output_file_extension" type="select" label="Output file extension" help="Default: fasta">
		<option value="default" selected="True">default</option>
                <option value="fa" >fa</option>
                <option value="seq">seq</option>
            </param>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
	   <collection name="fasta_collection" type="list" label="${tool.name} on ${on_string} : split seqences">
	      <discover_datasets pattern="(?P&lt;designation&gt;.+)" directory="contigs" format="fasta"/>
		 <!--<discover_datasets pattern="(?P&lt;designation&gt;.*)\.fa" format="fasta" directory="outdir"/>-->
           </collection>
    </outputs>
	
    <tests>
	 <test>
            <!-- #1 test -->
        </test>
    </tests>
    <help><![CDATA[
	    
.. class:: infomark

**What it does**
	    
*Fgenesh is a genome annotation tool*

**Input**
	    
- input file  -  Genome or de novo assembly file in FASTA format and repeat masking fasta file  

**Command line Example:**

- FGENESHPIPE/run_pipe.pl  human_prj.cfg  -l seq_1.list  -m seq_1N.list  -d results_1

- human_prj.cfg - a configuration file containing path to database, path gene matrix and the settings of the third party softwares
- seq_1.list - a list of chromosome / scaffolds (unmasked)
- seq_1N.ist - a list of chromosome / scaffolds (masked)
- results_1 - output folder


**Parameters:**

- matrix type - built-in index or select the index from the user history
- species matrix - select the gene matrix that matches the species of your input genome if built-in index in the matrix type is selected
- db type - built-in database or select the database from the user history
- reference database - fgenesh comes with Mammal DB / Non Mammal DB if built-in database in the db type is selected
- NR db type - built-in non-redundant database or select the non-redundant database from the user history
- NR database - select the non-redundant database for your species
- mRNAs - map known mRNA sequences to the genomic sequences (default: No). If Yes is selected, make sure .cdna, .pro and .dat files are available in the user history.
- ESTs - map ESTs to the genomic sequences (default: No) if Yes is selected, make sure there is ESTs fasta file available in the user history
- Predict GC - predict genes with GC donor splice sites or not (default:No)
- USE_READS - use reads info to improve gene models (default:No)
- Find homologs - find homologs for ab initio predicted genes (0 - no, 1 - yes)
- USE_PROTEINS - Using known proteins for prediction (default: No)
- INTRONIC_GENES - Predicting genes in long introns of other genes (default: No)

**Output**

- txt (resn3) - raw output produced by Fgenesh
- gff3 - gff3 file format converted from the Fgenesh resn3 file

 
.. class:: infomark

**Contributor**

Galaxy Australia wrapped the Fgenesh: the original software is available on this website `FGENESH <http://www.softberry.com/berry.phtml?topic=fgenesh_plus_plus&group=help&subgroup=pipelines>`_. Note: The software license needs to acquired prior to use.

	    
	]]></help>
</tool>
